- ARE YOU READY, KIDS?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all: AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
所有人：是，是，队长！
- I CAN'T HEAR YOU.
- 我听不到你说话。
all: AYE, AYE, CAPTAIN!
所有人：是，是，队长！
- ♪ OHH... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ WHO LIVES IN A PINEAPPLE
UNDER THE SEA? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- ♪ ABSORBENT AND YELLOW
AND POROUS IS HE ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- ♪ IF NAUTICAL NONSENSE
BE SOMETHING YOU WISH ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你所希望的 ♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
- ♪ THEN DROP ON THE DECK
AND FLOP LIKE A FISH ♪
- ♪ 然后掉到甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
- READY?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all: SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
所有：海绵宝宝！
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
海绵宝宝！
- SPONGEBOB
- 海绵宝宝
SQUAREPANTS!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
- [coughing]
- [咳嗽]
- JUST TWO MORE MINUTES,
PATRICK.
- 再过两分钟，
帕特里克。
- YUP.
- 是的。
- LOOK!
HERE HE COMES!
- 看！
他来了！
- WHO?
- WHO？
- 世界卫生组织？
- THANK YOU, MR. RANGER.
- 谢谢你，先生。游骑兵。
- YEAH, THANKS.
- 是的，谢谢。
- YES?
- 是的？
- AREN'T YOU FORGETTING
SOMETHING?
- 你没有忘记吗
有什么东西？
- YEAH.
SOMETHING.
- 是的。
某物。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
PLEASE SHOW ME YOUR...
请告诉我你的...
JELLYFISHING LICENSES.
捕捞水母许可证。
[both cheering]
[两人欢呼]
[jellyfish humming]
[水母嗡嗡声]
- PATRICK, LOOK!
- 帕特里克，看！
I CAUGHT A RARE BREED,
A GLOWING THREE-SPOT.
我抓到了一个稀有品种，
发光的三分球。
- HEY, I CAUGHT ONE TOO.
- 嘿，我也抓到了一只。
THIS ONE'S A FIVE-SPOT.
这是一个五点的。
[jellyfish hums]
[水母嗡嗡声]
- PATRICK, GUESS WHAT.
- 帕特里克，你猜怎么着。
- YOU LIKE IT HERE SO MUCH,
- 你非常喜欢这里，
YOU FEEL YOURSELF
BEING MOVED TO A SONG?
你感觉自己
被感动到一首歌？
- YES, YES, HOW DID YOU GUESS?
- 是的，是的，你是怎么猜到的？
- WELL, I KIND OF FEEL
A MOVEMENT COMING ON MYSELF.
- 嗯，我有点感觉
一场针对我自己的运动。
- LET'S JUST START
WITH THE SONG.
- 让我们开始吧
随着歌曲。
- YOU MEAN
THE JELLYFISHING SONG?
- 你的意思是
水母之歌？
- THAT'S THE ONE.
- 就是这个。
[pitch pipe toots]
[音调管嘟嘟声]
both: ♪ OH ♪
两人：♪哦♪
♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ IT'S THE JELLYFISHING SONG ♪
- [claps]
♪ 这是水母之歌 ♪
- [鼓掌]
both: ♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
两者：♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ EVERYONE SING ALONG ♪
[both clap]
♪ 大家一起唱 ♪
[两人鼓掌]
both: ♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
两者：♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ IT'S THE JELLYFISHING SONG ♪
[both clap]
♪ 这是水母之歌 ♪
[两人鼓掌]
both: ♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
两者：♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ EVERYONE SING ALONG ♪
♪ 大家一起唱 ♪
♪ I GO JELLYFISHING
IN THE MORNING ♪
♪ 我去钓水母
早上♪
- ♪ I JELLYFISH ALL THE NIGHT ♪
- ♪ 我整晚都在捉水母 ♪
- ♪ JELLYFISHING
IN THE AFTERNOON ♪
- ♪ 捕水母
下午♪
both: ♪ JELLYFISHING
MAKE ME FEEL ALL RIGHT ♪
两者：♪ 捕水母
让我感觉一切都好 ♪
[jellyfish humming]
[水母嗡嗡声]
♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ IT'S THE JELLYFISHING SONG ♪
[all clap]
♪ 这是水母之歌 ♪
[全体鼓掌]
both: ♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
两者：♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
- ♪ EVERYONE ♪
- ♪ 大家 ♪
♪ SING ♪
♪ 唱歌 ♪
both: ♪ EVERYONE SING ALONG ♪
两人：♪ 大家一起唱 ♪
ba-dum! dum!
巴杜姆！哑巴！
- ISN'T IT GREAT
THAT THESE MAJESTIC CREATURES
- 这不是很棒吗
这些雄伟的生物
HAVE JELLYFISH FIELDS
TO CALL THEIR HOME?
有水母区
打电话给他们的家？
- YOU BET.
- 你打赌。
AND IT'S HIGHWAY CONVENIENT TOO,
而且高速公路也很方便，
ACCORDING TO THAT BIG SIGN.
根据那个大标志。
- BIG SIGN?
I DIDN'T SEE A--
- 大标志？
我没看到——
JUMPING JELLYFISH,
THAT'S A BIG SIGN!
跳跃的水母，
这是一个大标志！
- AND IT SAYS, "FUTURE SITE
OF THE SHELLY SUPERHIGHWAY."
- 它说，“未来的站点
谢利高速公路。”
- SUPERHIGHWAY?
- 高速公路？
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
你知道这意味着什么吗？
- OH, YEAH, IT'S SORT OF LIKE
OTHER ROADS,
- 哦，是的，有点像
其他道路，
EXCEPT THERE ARE NO STOP S--
除非没有停止 S--
- I KNOW WHAT A SUPERHIGHWAY IS.
- 我知道什么是高速公路。
I MEAN
FOR ALL THESE JELLYFISH,
我的意思是
对于所有这些水母，
FOR US,
对于我们来说，
FOR JELLYFISH FIELD!
对于水母领域！
UH...SORRY.
呃……抱歉。
- SO WHAT YOU'RE SAYING
- 所以你在说什么
IS THAT IF THEY GO THROUGH
WITH THEIR PLANS
如果他们通过
与他们的计划
TO BUILD THIS NEW SUPERHIGHWAY
THROUGH JELLYFISH FIELDS
建设这条新的高速公路
穿过水母区
THAT EVERY SINGLE SPECIE
OF FLORA AND FAUNA
每个物种
动植物群
THAT MAKES THIS PLACE
THEIR HABITAT
这使得这个地方
他们的栖息地
WILL BE FORCED OUT OF
THE ECOSYSTEM THEY HAVE FORMED,
将被强制退出
他们形成的生态系统，
EFFECTIVELY BEING DESTROYED?
实际上被摧毁了吗？
- WELL, THAT'S
A SIMPLIFIED VERSION,
- 嗯，就是这样
简化版本，
BUT, YEAH, SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
但是，是的，类似的事情。
WHICH IS WHY
I HEREBY MAKE THIS SOLEMN VOW
这就是为什么
我在此郑重宣誓
TO STOP THIS
SO-CALLED SHELLY SUPERHIGHWAY
阻止这一切
所谓的雪莉高速公路
FROM EVER BEING BUILT.
自建成以来。
- 1,397,
1,398--WHOA!
1,398——哇！
- LARRY, YOU GOT TO HELP ME
STOP THE HIGHWAY.
- 拉里，你必须帮助我
停止高速公路。
- CAN'T RIGHT NOW, BRO.
- 现在不行，兄弟。
I GOT ABOUT 4,098 MORE REPS
TO DO.
我多做了 4,098 次
要做的事。
thud!
砰！
- MERMAID MAN!
BARNACLE BOY!
- 美人鱼男人！
藤壶男孩！
CERTAINLY WITH SUPERPOWERS
LIKE YOURS,
当然有超能力
像你一样，
WE CAN STOP THIS SUPERHIGHWAY.
我们可以阻止这条高速公路。
HMM.
唔。
- I'M SORRY, SPONGEBOB.
- 对不起，海绵宝宝。
I ACTUALLY WOULD LIKE
TO HELP,
我其实想要
为了提供帮助，
BUT I'M JUST TOO BUSY
RIGHT NOW.
但我太忙了
现在。
- TOO BUSY DOING WHAT?
- 忙着做什么？
- I'M TOO BUSY TELLING YOU,
"NO!"
- 我太忙告诉你了，
“不！”
[door slams]
[关门声]
- [whistling]
- [吹口哨]
[door clanks]
[门叮当作响]
PRIVATE SPONGEBOB!
AHOY!
私人海绵宝宝！
哎哟！
- CAPTAIN MR. KRABS, AHOY.
- 船长先生。螃蟹，哎呀。
- WHY, SPONGEBOB,
- 为什么，海绵宝宝，
THAT'S NOT YOUR USUAL
FOUR-FINGERED SALUTE.
这不寻常
四指敬礼。
- WELL, I GUESS I'M JUST UPSET
- 好吧，我想我只是心烦意乱
BECAUSE THEY'RE BUILDING
A HIGHWAY OVER JELLYFISH FIELDS.
因为他们正在建造
水母田上的高速公路。
[sniffles]
- WELL, SPONGEBOB,
[抽鼻子]
- 嗯，海绵宝宝，
I'D SURE HATE ME CUSTOMERS
TO SEE YOU LIKE THIS.
我肯定会讨厌我的顾客
看到你这样。
IS THERE ANYTHING I CAN DO
TO HELP?
有什么我可以做的吗
要帮忙吗？
- REALLY, MR. KRABS?
- 真的，先生。螃蟹？
- SURE, WHY NOT?
- 当然可以，为什么不呢？
- OH, MR. KRABS!
- 哦，先生。螃蟹！
I JUST KNOW THAT TOGETHER,
我只知道在一起，
WE CAN STOP
THAT NASTY OLD HIGHWAY
我们可以停下来
那条肮脏的旧高速公路
FROM GOING RIGHT THROUGH
JELLYFISH FIELDS.
从直接开始
水母区。
- UH, YOU'RE NOT TALKING ABOUT
- 呃，你不是在谈论
THE SHELLY SUPERHIGHWAY,
ARE YOU?
谢利高速公路，
你是吗？
- YEAH, WHY?
- 是啊，为什么？
- UH, WELL,
'CAUSE I'M ACTUALLY
- 呃，好吧，
因为我实际上
IN FAVOR
OF THAT HIGHWAY BEING BUILT.
赞成
正在修建的高速公路。
- NO!
- 不！
- YES,
I'VE ALREADY CALCULATED
- 是的，
我已经计算过了
HOW MANY NEW CUSTOMERS I'LL GET
ONCE IT'S FINISHED.
我会获得多少新客户
一旦完成。
YOU CAN SEE FOR YOURSELF
你可以亲自看看
ON THIS WHOLE SERIES OF CHARTS
AND DIAGRAMS I'VE DISPLAYED.
在这整个系列的图表上
和我展示的图表。
- CHARTS AND DIA--
- 图表和直径--
MR. KRABS, DIDN'T YOU SEE?
先生。蟹蟹，你没看见吗？
- SEE WHAT?
- THIS!
- 看到什么？
- 这！
ACCORDING TO THIS PLAN,
根据这个计划，
AFTER THE SHELLY SUPERHIGHWAY
GOES THROUGH JELLYFISH FIELDS,
经过谢利高速公路之后
穿过水母田，
IT GOES RIGHT OVER
THE KRUSTY KRAB.
一切都结束了
脆皮蟹。
HEY, LOOK.
嘿，看。
THERE YOU ARE, DESTITUTE
AND LIVING IN A CARDBOARD BOX.
你在那里，赤贫者
和生活在纸板箱里。
THEN IT DOES
SORT OF A LOOP-THE-LOOP
然后就这样了
有点像循环
BEFORE GOING STRAIGHT
INTO THE FRONT DOOR OF...
直行之前
进入...的前门
THE CHUM BUCKET.
密友桶。
- WHAT?
WHO APPROVED THIS PLAN?
- 什么？
谁批准了这个计划？
- "PLAN APPROVED AND SPONSORED
BY SHELDON PLANKTON ENTERPRISES,
- “计划已获批准和赞助
由谢尔顿浮游生物企业提供，
A DIVISION
OF NO FUN INCORPORATED."
一个部门
没有任何乐趣。”
- COME ON, LAD,
LET'S GO GIVE THAT PLANKTON
- 来吧，小伙子，
让我们去提供浮游生物
A PIECE OF OUR MINDS.
我们的想法。
- THINK THIS PIECE
WILL GET THE POINT ACROSS?
- 想想这首曲子
能明白要点吗？
- ALL RIGHT, PLANKTON,
- 好吧，浮游生物，
IT'S EUGENE KRABS HERE
WITH WHAT'S-HIS-NAME.
这是尤金·克拉布斯
与他的名字有关。
NOW, COME ON OUT!
- I CAN'T.
现在，出来吧！
- 我不能。
- COME ON OUTSIDE
AND TAKE WHAT'S COMING TO YOU.
- 到外面来
接受即将到来的一切。
- I REALLY CAN'T COME OUTSIDE.
- 我真的不能出去。
- WHY NOT?
- 为什么不呢？
- BECAUSE I'M ALREADY OUT HERE,
YOU BUMBLING BOTTOM-FEEDERS.
- 因为我已经在这里了
你们这些笨手笨脚的底层喂食者。
OPEN YOUR EYES,
FOR CRYING OUT LOUD!
睁开你的眼睛，
为了大声哭喊！
- OH, SORRY.
- 哦，抱歉。
- NOW, WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT,
ANYWAY?
- 现在，这是怎么回事，
无论如何？
- DON'T PLAY COY WITH US,
SHELLY.
- 不要对我们表现得忸怩作态，
雪莉。
WE BOTH KNOW
YOU'VE BEEN UP TO NO GOOD.
我们都知道
你没有做好事。
NOW, START TALKING.
现在，开始说话。
- ALL RIGHT,
SO I'VE BEEN STEALING YOUR MAIL
- 好吧，
所以我一直在偷你的邮件
FOR THE PAST FIVE YEARS,
BIG WHOOP.
在过去的五年里，
大呼。
- NOT THAT.
- WHAT? YOU'VE BEEN WHAT?
- 不是那样。
- 什么？你曾经是什么？
- WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
THAT NEW SUPERHIGHWAY
- 我们正在谈论
那条新的高速公路
YOU'RE PLANNING ON BUILDING.
您正在计划建造。
AND IN CASE YOU DIDN'T KNOW,
如果你不知道，
IT'S GONNA DESTROY
JELLYFISH FIELDS.
它会毁灭
水母区。
NOT TO MENTION THAT YOUR PLAN
IS STUPID AND DUMB
更不用说你的计划
又蠢又笨
AND DUMB AND STUPID.
又蠢又蠢。
- WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'VE BEEN WHAT?
- 等一下。
你曾经是什么？
- WELL, THAT CERTAINLY WAS
AN INTERESTING SERIES OF WORDS
- 嗯，那确实是
一系列有趣的单词
THAT JUST TUMBLED OUT
PAST YOUR TEETH AND LIPS,
刚刚跌落的
经过你的牙齿和嘴唇，
BUT FRANKLY, MY DEAR SPONGE,
I DON'T GIVE A BARNACLE.
但坦白说，我亲爱的海绵，
我不给藤壶。
- HUH?
- 嗯？
- I DON'T KNOW.
- 我不知道。
- FORGET IT.
- 忘了它。
EVEN IF I WANTED TO STOP
即使我想停下来
THE SHELLY SUPERHIGHWAY
FROM BEING BUILT,
谢利高速公路
从建成之日起，
IT WOULD BE IMPOSSIBLE.
这是不可能的。
- WHY?
- 为什么？
- BECAUSE THE WHOLE CITY
HAS ALREADY APPROVED IT.
- 因为整个城市
已经批准了。
SEE FOR YOURSELF
亲自看看
THROUGH THIS
CONVENIENTLY TIMED FLASHBACK.
通过这个
方便的定时闪回。
[crowd murmuring]
[人群窃窃私语]
- ORDER. ORDER.
[gavel pounding]
- 命令。命令。
[木槌敲击]
ORDER IN THE MEETING HALL.
[clunking]
会议厅内的秩序。
[叮当声]
NOW, ALL THOSE IN FAVOR
OF PAVING OVER JELLYFISH FIELDS
现在，所有赞成者
水母区的铺路
AND BUILDING
THE SHELLY SUPERHIGHWAY,
和建筑
谢利高速公路，
RAISE YOUR RIGHT FIN AND SAY,
"AYE."
举起你的右鳍并说：
“是啊。”
all: AYE.
所有人：是的。
- EVERYBODY ELSE JUST SIT THERE,
QUIETLY.
- 其他人就坐在那里，
安静地。
- I LIKE HIGHWAYS.
- 我喜欢高速公路。
- I LIKE THINGS
THAT ARE SUPER.
- 我喜欢的东西
太棒了。
- AND I LIKE SAYING, "AYE."
- 我喜欢说，“是的。”
OH, WHY DID I SAY, "AYE"?
哦，我为什么说“是”？
- SEEMS AS THOUGH
THE AYES HAVE IT.
- 看起来好像
同意的人拥有它。
NOW, IF YOU'LL EXCUSE ME,
现在，请原谅我，
I'VE GOT
SUPERHIGHWAY PREPARATIONS
我有
高速公路准备工作
TO BE ATTENDING TO.
正在参加。
TOODLES.
工具。
- WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO NOW,
MR. KRABS?
- 我们现在要做什么，
先生。螃蟹？
- WELL, I'M GONNA DO
THE ONLY THING I CAN DO
- 好吧，我会做
我唯一能做的
WHEN ME CHARACTER IS TESTED
BY INSURMOUNTABLE ODDS:
当我的性格受到考验时
难以克服的赔率：
LIE ON ME BACK
AND SOB LOUDLY.
躺在我背上
大声抽泣。
- NORMALLY, MR. KRABS,
- 通常情况下，先生。螃蟹，
I WOULD LIE ON MY BACK
AND SOB LOUDLY TOO,
我会仰卧
也大声抽泣，
BUT I AM NOT GIVING UP.
但我不会放弃。
THERE'S STILL ONE CITIZEN
IN BIKINI BOTTOM
还有一名公民
比基尼下装
WHO WON'T SIT STILL
谁不会坐以待毙
IN THE FACE
OF THIS OUTRAGEOUS INJUSTICE.
当面
这种令人发指的不公正行为。
[mellow harmonica
and guitar music]
[醇厚的口琴
和吉他音乐]
both: ♪ CHUM BUCKET ♪
两者：♪ 美味桶 ♪
♪ SLUDGE BUCKET ♪
♪ 污泥桶 ♪
♪ HIGHWAY FLY AWAY ♪
♪ 高速公路飞走 ♪
♪ LILY LIVER ♪
♪ 百合肝 ♪
♪ PIZZA GIVER ♪
♪ 送披萨的人 ♪
♪ MASHED POTATO ♪
♪ 土豆泥 ♪
♪ KELP TOMATO ♪
♪ 海带番茄 ♪
♪ ALL WE ARE TRYING TO SAY ♪
♪ 我们想说的一切 ♪
♪ IS GIVE JELLYFISH FIELDS ♪
♪ 赠送水母田 ♪
♪ A CHANCE ♪
♪ 有机会 ♪
♪ ♪
♪ KETCHUP BOTTLE ♪
♪ 番茄酱瓶 ♪
♪ NET AND GOGGLE ♪
♪ 网和护目镜 ♪
♪ TOLLBOOTH ♪
♪ 收费站 ♪
♪ ROTTEN TOOTH ♪
♪ 烂牙 ♪
♪ FREEWAY PLAN ♪
♪ 高速公路计划 ♪
♪ TOAST AND JAM ♪
♪ 吐司和果酱 ♪
♪ MERMAID MAN ♪
♪ 美人鱼男 ♪
♪ GARBAGE CAN ♪
♪ 垃圾桶 ♪
♪ CITRUS FRUIT ♪
♪ 柑橘类水果 ♪
♪ COMBAT BOOT ♪
♪ 战斗靴 ♪
♪ GIVE A HOOT ♪
♪ 发出一声 ♪
♪ GORILLA SUIT ♪
♪ 大猩猩套装 ♪
♪ ALL WE ARE TRYING TO SAY ♪
♪ 我们想说的一切 ♪
♪ IS GIVE JELLYFISH FIELDS ♪
♪ 赠送水母田 ♪
♪ A CHANCE ♪
♪ 有机会 ♪
[door slams]
[关门声]
♪ FIGHT AND DIE ♪
♪ 战斗而死 ♪
♪ HAM ON RYE ♪
♪ 黑麦火腿 ♪
♪ LARRY'S THIGH ♪
♪ 拉里的大腿 ♪
♪ BATTLE CRY ♪
♪ 战斗呐喊 ♪
♪ MUSTARD SQUIRT ♪
♪ 芥末汁 ♪
♪ LONG-SLEEVED SHIRT ♪
♪ 长袖衬衫 ♪
♪ SELF-ASSERT ♪
♪ 自作主张 ♪
♪ HIT THE DIRT ♪
♪ 击中污垢 ♪
♪ KRUSTY KRAB ♪
♪ 脆皮蟹 ♪
♪ SMASH AND GRAB ♪
♪ 粉碎并抓取 ♪
♪ BARG'N-MART ♪
♪ 巴格尼玛特 ♪
♪ GROCERY CART ♪
♪ 杂货车 ♪
♪ ALL WE ARE TRYING TO SAY ♪
♪ 我们想说的一切 ♪
♪ IS GIVE JELLYFISH FIELDS ♪
♪ 赠送水母田 ♪
♪ A CHANCE ♪
♪ 有机会 ♪
♪ ♪
♪ CEOs ♪
♪ 首席执行官 ♪
♪ GARY'S TOES ♪
♪ 加里的脚趾 ♪
♪ SQUIDWARD'S NOSE ♪
♪ 章鱼哥的鼻子 ♪
♪ PANTY HOSE ♪
♪ 连裤袜 ♪
♪ ROCKING CHAIR ♪
♪ 摇椅 ♪
♪ WASH AND WEAR ♪
♪ 洗后穿 ♪
♪ EMPTY STARE ♪
♪ 空洞的凝视 ♪
♪ PATRICK'S HAIR ♪
♪ 帕特里克的头发 ♪
♪ GREEN TREES ♪
♪ 绿树 ♪
♪ SANDY'S FLEAS ♪
♪ 桑迪的跳蚤 ♪
♪ RISE AND SHINE ♪
♪ 崛起并闪耀 ♪
♪ LEMON LIME ♪
♪ 柠檬青柠 ♪
♪ OUT OF TIME ♪
♪ 不合时宜 ♪
♪ SQUIGGLY LINE ♪
♪ 波浪线 ♪
♪ TAKE A STAND ♪
♪ 表明立场 ♪
♪ HAND IN HAND ♪
♪ 手拉手 ♪
♪ ALL WE ARE TRYING TO SAY ♪
♪ 我们想说的一切 ♪
♪ IS GIVE JELLYFISH FIELDS ♪
♪ 赠送水母田 ♪
[sitar chord]
[西塔琴和弦]
♪ A CHANCE ♪
♪ 有机会 ♪
[crowd booing]
[人群嘘声]
- IT'S WORKING, PATRICK.
- 成功了，帕特里克。
THEY'RE BOOING THE HIGHWAY.
他们在高速公路上发出嘘声。
LOOKS LIKE OUR MESSAGE
看起来像我们的信息
HAS REALLY STARTED
GETTING THROUGH TO THE PEOPLE.
已经真正开始了
深入人心。
LET'S PLAY ANOTHER SONG
WHILE THEIR HEARTS ARE OPEN.
让我们再演奏一首歌曲
当他们的心敞开时。
HEY, WAIT A MINUTE.
嘿，等一下。
THIS IS ONE OF OUR FLYERS.
这是我们的一张传单。
THEY'RE PELTING US
WITH OUR OWN PAMPHLETS.
他们向我们投掷
附有我们自己的小册子。
WHAT DOES THIS MEAN?
这意味着什么？
- I COULDN'T TELL YOU.
- 我无法告诉你。
- I'LL TELL YOU WHAT IT MEANS.
- 我会告诉你这意味着什么。
IT MEANS THIS.
这就是这个意思。
[tambourine jangling]
[手鼓叮当作响]
- IT MEANS YOU HATE TAMBOURINES?
- 这意味着你讨厌铃鼓？
- NO, IT MEANS--
[siren wails]
- 不，这意味着——
[警报声]
- ALL RIGHT,
YOU GUYS THE HIGHWAY HATERS?
- 好吧，
你们是讨厌高速公路的人吗？
- YES, BUT WITH GOOD REASON,
SIR.
- 是的，但有充分的理由，
先生。
YOU SEE,
WITHOUT JELLYFISH FIELDS,
你看，
没有水母场，
JELLYFISH WILL HAVE TO FIND
A NEW HOME AND--
水母必须找到
一个新家和——
- ALL RIGHT, YOU TWO,
YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
- 好吧，你们两个，
你被捕了。
- WHAT FOR?
- 做什么的？
- UNLICENSED USE OF A SITAR.
- 未经许可使用西塔琴。
- BUT MY GRANDMA
GAVE ME THIS SITAR.
- 但是我的奶奶
给了我这把西塔琴。
IT DIDN'T COME WITH A LICENSE.
它没有许可证。
- YEAH, WELL,
NEITHER DID THIS.
- 是啊，好吧，
这也没有。
all: HIGHWAY! HIGHWAY!
所有人：高速公路！公路！
HIGHWAY! HIGHWAY!
公路！公路！
[doors slam]
[关上门]
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
[flashbulbs popping]
[闪光灯爆响]
[cheering continues]
[欢呼声继续]
- PATRICK, I'M SCARED.
- 帕特里克，我很害怕。
- SPONGEBOB, I'LL NEVER FORGET
WHAT MY GREAT-UNCLE CLETUS SAID
- 海绵宝宝，我永远不会忘记
我的叔祖父克莱图斯说的话
RIGHT BEFORE HE WAS ARRESTED
DURING A FREEDOM MARCH.
就在他被捕之前
在自由游行期间。
- WHAT WAS THAT?
- 那是什么？
- IT'S WHERE A BUNCH OF PEOPLE
GO WALKING DOWN THE STREET AND--
- 这是一群人的地方
沿着街道走，然后——
- I KNOW WHAT
A FREEDOM MARCH IS, PATRICK.
- 我知道什么
自由游行是，帕特里克。
I MEAN, WHAT DID HE SAY?
我的意思是，他说什么？
- OH, YEAH.
- 哦，是的。
HE SAID, "LET NOT YOUR HEART
WALK AWAY FROM YOU
他说：“不要让你的心
远离你
LEST YOUR MIND GROW LEGS
AND FOLLOW IT."
以免你的头脑长出腿来
并遵循它。”
- WOW, YOUR UNCLE SOUNDS LIKE
A PRETTY SMART GUY, PATRICK.
- 哇，你叔叔听起来像
帕特里克，一个非常聪明的人。
WHAT HAPPENED TO HIM
AFTER HE WAS ARRESTED?
他发生了什么事
他被捕后？
- I DON'T KNOW.
- 我不知道。
HE WAS NEVER HEARD FROM AGAIN.
从此再也没有他的消息。
[both yelp]
[两人都尖叫]
[tires squealing]
[轮胎吱吱声]
- SEE YOU LATER, LONGHAIRS.
- 再见，长毛们。
- BYE.
- BYE!
- 再见。
- 再见！
- IT'S A WIG.
- SEE YOU LATER.
- 这是假发。
- 稍后见。
THANKS FOR THE LIFT.
感谢您乘坐电梯。
THEY LEFT US
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
他们离开了我们
在偏僻的地方。
- WELL, THIS ISN'T
THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
- 嗯，这不是
偏僻的地方。
WE'RE ACTUALLY
RIGHT ON THE EDGE OF NOWHERE.
我们实际上是
就在无处可寻的边缘。
- WELL, AT LEAST
IT ISN'T RAINING.
- 嗯，至少
没有下雨。
[thunder booming]
[雷霆轰鸣]
- I'M NOT READY
TO GIVE UP JUST YET.
- 我还没准备好
暂时放弃。
- I AM.
- 我是。
- IF WE COULD JUST COME UP
- 如果我们能上来的话
WITH A BETTER WAY
TO REACH THE PEOPLE,
有更好的方法
为了接触人们，
SOMETHING EVERYBODY
CAN SEE AND HEAR.
每个人都有一些东西
可以看到和听到。
- YOU MEAN LIKE A PARADE?
- 你的意思是像游行一样？
- OH, A PARADE!
- 哦，游行！
PATRICK, HOW DID YOU COME UP
WITH SUCH A BRILLIANT IDEA?
帕特里克，你怎么来的
有这么绝妙的主意吗？
- THERE'S ONE GOING BY
RIGHT THERE.
- 有人经过
就在那里。
[festive marching band music]
【节日军乐队音乐】
♪ ♪
[horn honks]
[喇叭鸣响]
[whip cracking]
[鞭子断裂]
[rock music]
[摇滚乐]
[bagpipe music]
[风笛音乐]
♪ ♪
[choral scale]
[合唱音阶]
- THAT CERTAINLY IS A PARADE.
- 这当然是游行。
- LOOK!
- [gasps]
- 看！
- [喘气]
PLANKTON,
浮游生物，
DRIVING A BIG TRACTOR.
驾驶大型拖拉机。
THIS DOESN'T LOOK GOOD AT ALL,
PATRICK.
这看起来一点都不好，
帕特里克。
- DOES THIS?
[grunting]
- 这是吗？
[咕噜声]
- COME ON.
LET'S GO FOLLOW HIM.
- 快点。
我们去跟随他吧。
[festive marching band music]
【节日军乐队音乐】
♪ ♪
- PEOPLE OF BIKINI BOTTOM.
- 比基尼下装的人。
[crowd murmuring]
[人群窃窃私语]
- DID YOU HEAR THAT?
- 你听到了吗？
- I'M HEARING THE VOICES AGAIN.
- 我又听到那些声音了。
- LOOK!
UP THERE.
- 看！
上面。
- TODAY MARKS A NEW--
- 今天标志着一个新的日子——
[crowd murmuring]
[人群窃窃私语]
- STOP MURMURING!
- 别再抱怨了！
THANK YOU.
谢谢。
AS I WAS SAYING, TODAY MARKS
THE BEGINNING OF A NEW--
正如我所说，今天标志着
新的开始——
all: ♪ FOR ♪
全部：♪ 为了 ♪
♪ HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW ♪
♪ 他是一个非常好的小伙子 ♪
♪ FOR HE'S A JOLLY GOOD FELLOW ♪
♪ 因为他是一个快乐的好家伙 ♪
♪ FOR HE'S A JOLLY-- ♪
- SHUT UP!
♪ 因为他是个快乐的人—— ♪
- 闭嘴！
- HUH?
WHAT?
- 嗯？
什么？
- TODAY MARKS
A NEW BEGINNING
- 今日标记
新的开始
FOR BIKINI BOTTOM!
比基尼下装！
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
NOW IT'S TIME TO PAVE OUR WAY
DOWN THE ROAD TO SUCCESS.
现在是时候铺路了
迈向成功之路。
[engine rattles]
[发动机嘎嘎声]
[jellyfish humming]
[水母嗡嗡声]
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
[inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
I LOVE THE SMELL OF HOT TAR
IN THE MORNING.
我喜欢热焦油的味道
早上。
YEAH, BABY!
是的，宝贝！
[chuckles]
[笑声]
HEY, YOU THERE.
嘿，你在那里。
ARE YOU TRYING
TO GET YOURSELF CRUSHED?
你在尝试吗
让自己被压垮？
- I WON'T LET YOU DO IT,
PLANKTON.
- 我不会让你这样做，
浮游生物。
IF YOU'RE GONNA
PAVE OVER JELLYFISH FIELDS,
如果你要
铺平水母田，
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO PAVE OVER ME FIRST.
你将会拥有
首先给我铺路。
- WHOO, YOUR WISH
IS MY COMMAND, SPONGE.
- 哇，你的愿望
这是我的命令，海绵。
[engine roars]
[发动机轰鸣声]
smack!
咂！
- IS THAT ALL YOU GOT?
- 这就是你所得到的一切吗？
[tar hissing]
[焦油嘶嘶声]
[festive marching band music]
【节日军乐队音乐】
♪ ♪
[jellyfish humming]
[水母嗡嗡声]
[festive horn music]
【喜庆的号角音乐】
♪ ♪
KNOCK IT OFF, PATRICK.
别闹了，帕特里克。
- I USED TO DREAM
OF ME RESTAURANT
- 我曾经梦想过
我的餐厅
HAVING EASY HIGHWAY ACCESS.
高速公路交通便利。
- YEAH, BUT THIS IS MORE
LIKE HIGHWAY EXCESS.
- 是的，但这更重要
比如高速公路超限。
- WELL, I'M GONNA GO
SOAK MY TENTACLES.
- 好吧，我要走了
浸泡我的触手。
IT'S COLD IN HERE
UNDER ALL THIS CONCRETE.
这里很冷
在这一切混凝土之下。
- BUT, SQUIDWARD,
YOU CAN'T LEAVE.
-但是，章鱼哥，
你不能离开。
WHAT IF WE HAVE A CUSTOMER?
如果我们有客户怎么办？
- REALLY?
- 真的吗？
WE HAVEN'T HAD A CUSTOMER
我们还没有客户
SINCE THE DAY
THIS HIGHWAY WAS BUILT.
从那天起
这条高速公路建成了。
- UH, SQUIDWARD, IT'S
TECHNICALLY A SUPERHIGHWAY.
- 呃，章鱼哥，是这样
从技术上讲是一条高速公路。
- I DON'T CARE WHAT IT IS.
- 我不在乎它是什么。
I'M OUT OF HERE.
我要离开这里了。
- BUT, SQUIDWARD--
- NO.
-但是，章鱼哥--
- 不。
NO, SPONGEBOB.
不，海绵宝宝。
SQUIDWARD'S RIGHT.
章鱼哥是对的。
I THINK IT'S HIGH TIME
WE STARTED ACCEPTING FACTS.
我认为现在是时候了
我们开始接受事实。
[electronic screeching]
[电子尖叫声]
- I'M ON IT, MR. KRABS.
- 我已经开始了，先生。螃蟹。
- NO, BOY-O, NOT THAT KIND.
- 不，男孩，不是那样的。
- MR. KRABS,
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
- 先生。螃蟹，
你在说什么？
- THE KRUSTY KRAB
CAN'T STAY IN BUSINESS.
- 脆皮蟹
无法继续经营。
NOT LIKE THIS.
- IT CAN'T?
不是这样的。
- 不能吗？
- NO, SPONGEBOB.
- 不，海绵宝宝。
IT'S TIME TO ACTIVATE
PLAN ZED DASH NINER NINER.
是时候激活了
ZED 冲刺九人计划。
- ZED DASH NINER NINER?
- ZED DASH 九九？
- EUGENE, WHAT IS
PLAN ZED DASH NINER NINER?
- 尤金，什么是
ZED DASH 九九计划？
AND MORE IMPORTANTLY,
HOW DOES IT AFFECT ME?
更重要的是，
它对我有何影响？
- PLAN ZED
DASH NINER NINER IS...
- ZED计划
DASH NINER NINER 是...
[horn honks and engine rumbles]
[喇叭声和发动机隆隆声]
I'M--
[cars zooming, horns honking]
我是——
[汽车疾驰，喇叭鸣响]
I'M--
[cars zooming, horns honking]
我是——
[汽车疾驰，喇叭鸣响]
I'M SELLING THE KRABBY PATTY
SECRET FORMULA TO PLANKTON.
我要卖蟹肉饼
浮游生物的秘密配方。
- EUGENE.
- 尤金。
- I HAVE NO CHOICE.
- 我别无选择。
AND STOP CALLING ME EUGENE.
别再叫我尤金了。
- TELL ME THAT I'M DREAMING.
- 告诉我我在做梦。
[moans]
[呻吟声]
- NOT THIS TIME,
LITTLE FELLA.
- 这次不是，
小家伙。
- [sobbing]
- [抽泣]
- UHH.
LOWER.
- 呃。
降低。
A LITTLE LOWER.
低一点。
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
是的，就是这样。
NOW, WHO COULD THAT BE
DURING MY HOUR OF TRIUMPH?
现在，那会是谁
在我的胜利时刻？
HOW APPROPRIATE.
[snickers]
多么合适啊。
[窃笑]
- PLANKTON,
I'M READY TO NEGOTIATE A PRICE
- 浮游生物，
我已准备好协商价格
FOR ME SECRET FORMULA.
对我来说秘密公式。
- OH, GOODY.
- 哦，太好了。
LET ME JUST WIND MY WATCH.
让我给手表上发条。
- WHAT FOR?
- 做什么的？
- 'CAUSE I'M GONNA LOVE
EVERY MINUTE OF THIS.
- 因为我会爱
这其中的每一分钟。
[faint humming]
[微弱的嗡嗡声]
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
你听到了吗？
KAREN, IS THAT YOU?
凯伦，是你吗？
- UP THERE.
- 上面。
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[jellyfish humming]
[水母嗡嗡声]
- WHOA, NELLY.
- 哇哦，内莉。
- FIRST I LOST
JELLYFISH FIELDS.
- 首先我输了
水母区。
AND--
和 -
- AND WHAT?
- 还有什么？
- AND NOW I'VE LOST
THE ONLY JOB I EVER WANTED.
- 现在我输了
这是我唯一想要的工作。
[sobs]
[抽泣]
- LOOK AT IT THIS WAY.
- 这样看。
I DON'T HAVE TO SEE YOU
EVERY DAY NOW.
我不必见你
现在的每一天。
OH, THIS REALLY
COULD BE THE START
哦，这真的是
可能是一个开始
OF SOMETHING BEAUTIFUL.
美丽的事物。
[zapping]
OW!
[电击]
噢！
WHAT IN THE NAME OF--
- SQUIDWARD, LOOK!
以什么名义——
- 章鱼哥，看！
- WHAT AM I LOOKING--
[screams]
- 我在看什么--
[尖叫声]
- ALL THE JELLYFISH WHO USED
TO LIVE IN JELLYFISH FIELDS
- 所有使用过的水母
生活在水母区
ARE COMING TO BIKINI BOTTOM!
即将推出比基尼泳装！
- YEAH, BUT FOR SOME REASON,
- 是的，但是出于某种原因，
I DON'T THINK IT'S TO DISTRIBUTE
HOLIDAY GIFT BASKETS.
我不认为这是为了分发
节日礼品篮。
- AW, YOU DON'T?
- 哦，你不知道吗？
[jellyfish humming]
[水母嗡嗡声]
[people screaming]
[人们尖叫]
- HEY, YOU KNOW, PLANKTON,
- 嘿，你知道，浮游生物，
LET'S JUST
TALK ABOUT THIS LATER.
让我们来吧
稍后再谈。
I THINK I'M JUST GONNA
RUN FOR ME LIFE.
我想我只是要
为我的生活而奔跑。
- WAIT!
I'M COMING WITH YOU.
- 等待！
我和你一起去。
[chokes]
[窒息]
NO!
不！
[zapping]
NOT THE EYE.
[电击]
不是眼睛。
NOT THE EYE!
[zapping continues]
不是眼睛！
[继续攻击]
[static humming]
[静态嗡嗡声]
- CHAOS RUNS RAMPANT
IN BIKINI BOTTOM.
- 混乱猖獗
比基尼下装。
THAT'S RIGHT, FOLKS.
没错，伙计们。
THIS IS NEWS REPORTER BEN BLENNY
这是新闻记者本·布莱尼
STANDING IN FOR PERCH PERKINS,
WHO'S OUT TODAY
代表PERCH PERKINS，
今天谁出局了
WITH A TERRIBLE CASE
OF INDIGESTION.
一个可怕的案例
消化不良。
AND WE ARE COMING TO YOU LIVE
DURING DAY THREE
我们将为您现场直播
第三天
OF WHAT APPEARS TO BE
BIKINI BOTTOM'S WORST--
看起来是什么
最差的比基尼泳裤——
- AM I ON TELEVISION?
- 我在电视上吗？
- YES, SIR, YOU ARE.
- 是的，先生，你是。
WOULD YOU CARE
TO SAY A FEW WORDS--
你会关心吗
说几句话——
- HI, MOM.
HI, DAD.
- 嗨，妈妈。
嗨，爸爸。
HEY, DR. SLEEN.
HEY, JENNIFER.
嘿，博士。安静。
嘿，詹妮弗。
HEY, SALLY.
HEY, FRANCES.
嘿，莎莉。
嘿，弗朗西斯。
HEY, MABEL.
HEY, JULIE.
嘿，梅布尔。
嘿，朱莉。
HEY, ABIGAIL!
嘿，阿比盖尔！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
NOW THEY'LL HAVE TO LISTEN.
现在他们必须倾听。
- AND THERE'S MY PALS
IN ALTOONA
- 这是我的朋友们
在阿尔图纳
AND THE GANG
AT THE PUDGY FLIPPER.
和帮派
在矮胖的脚蹼处。
- THANK YOU.
- 谢谢。
HELLO, LITTLE BOY,
你好，小男孩，
HOW ABOUT SAYING A FEW WORDS
INTO THE CAMERA
说几句话怎么样
进入镜头
ABOUT THE CURRENT CRISIS?
关于当前的危机？
- UM, OKAY.
- 嗯，好吧。
SORRY, I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS.
- [screaming]
抱歉，我有点紧张。
- [尖叫]
- THAT'S UNDERSTANDABLE.
JUST TALK NICE AND CLEAR.
- 这是可以理解的。
只要说得好听、清楚就好。
- WELL, OKAY, I GUESS.
- 嗯，好吧，我想。
ALL I HAVE TO SAY
我要说的就是
IS THAT, UM...
是这样吗，嗯……
THAT PROBABLY--
那可能是——
STOP THE MADNESS!
停止疯狂！
WE NEED TO GIVE JELLYFISH FIELDS
BACK TO THE JELLYFISH.
我们需要提供水母栖息地
回到水母。
IF WE RESTORE
THEIR NATURAL HABITAT,
如果我们恢复
他们的自然栖息地，
THEN THEY WILL GO IN PEACE,
然后他们就会平静地离开，
AND BALANCE WILL ONCE AGAIN
BE RESTORED TO OUR LAND.
平衡将再次实现
恢复我们的土地。
SO WHAT DO YOU SAY, EVERYBODY?
那么大家觉得呢？
WILL YOU HELP ME?
你会帮助我吗？
all: NO!
所有人：不！
- YOU'RE KIDDING, RIGHT?
- 你在开玩笑吧？
all: YES!
所有人：是的！
- WELL, ALL RIGHT.
- 好吧，好吧。
EVERYBODY, FOLLOW ME.
大家跟我来。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
OKAY, EVERYONE,
好的，大家，
SAY GOOD-BYE TO THE WORST THING
TO HAPPEN TO THIS TOWN
向最糟糕的事情说再见
这个小镇将会发生什么
SINCE 97¢ STORES.
自 97 美分商店起。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
[metallic squealing]
[金属尖叫声]
[all gasp]
- [snickering]
[全都喘气]
- [窃笑]
GOOD EFFORT, SPONGEDOPE,
尽力而为，海绵宝宝，
BUT YOU CAN'T
TEAR UP MY HIGHWAY.
但你不能
撕毁我的高速公路。
IT'S INDESTRUCTIBLE!
它是坚不可摧的！
- NOT IF WE HAVE ANYTHING
TO DO WITH IT.
- 如果我们有任何东西就不会
处理它。
- LARRY LOBSTER!
- 拉里·龙虾！
- THAT'S RIGHT, PAL,
BUT THAT'S NOT ALL.
- 没错，朋友，
但这还不是全部。
- SANDY SQUIRREL!
- 桑迪松鼠！
MRS. PUFF!
太太。噗！
MERMAID MAN
AND BARNACLE BOY!
美人鱼人
还有藤壶男孩！
PATRICK!
帕特里克！
- SHOOT. SHOOT. SHOOT.
- 射击。射击。射击。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- AND SQUIDWARD!
-还有章鱼哥！
- NOPE, THAT'S EVERYBODY.
- 不，大家都是这样。
- PUSH.
- 推。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
HARDER!
更难！
- HARDER STILL!
- 更难！
- YOU HEARD
THE LITTLE SQUARE GUY.
- 你听到了
小方块家伙。
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
- WAIT.
- 等待。
I DIDN'T COUNT
ON ALL OF YOU WORKING TOGETHER.
我没有数
感谢你们所有人的共同努力。
[metallic squealing]
crunch!
[金属尖叫声]
紧缩！
MY HIGHWAY!
我的高速公路！
STOP!
停止！
YOU CAN'T!
你不能！
smack!
咂！
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
- PRAISE NEPTUNE.
- 赞美海王星。
- ♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
- ♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ IT'S THE JELLYFISHING SONG ♪
[all clap]
♪ 这是水母之歌 ♪
[全体鼓掌]
♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ EVERYONE SING ALONG ♪
[all clap]
♪ 大家一起唱 ♪
[全体鼓掌]
all: ♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
全部：♪ 果冻 LELLY LELLY 果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ IT'S THE JELLYFISHING SONG ♪
[all clap]
♪ 这是水母之歌 ♪
[全体鼓掌]
♪ JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY,
JELLY LELLY LELLY JELLY ♪
♪ 果冻莱利莱利果冻，
果冻莱利莱利果冻 ♪
♪ EVERYONE SING ♪
♪ 大家都唱歌 ♪
- EVERYONE SING ALONG.
- 大家一起唱。
Captioning byCaptionMax
www.captionmax.com
字幕由 CaptionMax 提供
[lilting ukulele music]
[轻快的尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
[kids laughing]
[孩子们笑]